菲比  帮我挑适合莫妮卡的订婚戒指好吗
Pheebs, would you help me pick out an engagement ring for Monica?
我都挑花眼了  好难挑喔
l can't figure this out. It’s so hard!
我要选蒂芬尼切割法还是...
Should l get her a Tiffany cut
公主方切割法还是...
or a princess cut or a...?
被纸割法
Paper cut!
你有告诉其他人吗
Have you told anyone else?
没有  我没告诉其他人
No, I dont want to tell anybody else
因为我怕被莫妮卡发现
because I don’t want Monica to find out.
可是你告诉我了
You told me.
因为我信任你  你是我的死党之一
Because l trust you, you’re one of my best friends
而且你在我看戒指目录时闯进来
and you saw me looking at ring brochures.
进房不敲门  再次大有斩获
Once again, not knocking pays off.
-当时你不是在蹲马桶就更好了  -我有同感
- l wish you hadn't been on the toilet. - Me too.
-钱德勒  要不要去喝咖啡  -好啊  走吧
- So Chandler, wanna go to the coffeehouse? - Oh, all right.
去咖啡馆吧
Yeah, coffee house.
太好了  我们正想找你们下去呢
Oh perfect, we were just gonna see if you wanted to go.
不要  我们要去别家
Oh well, we don’t because we got the other pl-place.
真没礼貌
How rude.
抱歉  你要吃吗
Oh, I'm sorry. You wanna bite?
你和保罗交往得怎样
So how are things going with Paul?
很好
Good.
只不过他很内敛
Although, you know, he's a private guy.
真想让他稍微敞开心胸  分享心情
Y’know, I wish I could get him to open up a little bit, share some feelings.
简单
That's easy.
你把想象成打不开的罐子就对了
You just have to think of him as a-as a jar of pickles that won't open.
所以你的意思是
So what are you saying;
我应该拿他去冲热水  然后抓他的头撞桌子吗
l should run him under hot water and bang his head against a table?
不是  那是逼问真相的手法
No that's what you do when you want to get the truth out of someone.
-宝贝  我来啦  -你来啦
-Hi honey. -Hi.
-瞧好了  -好
- Watch this. - Okay.
-好啊  保罗  -你好  菲比
- Hey, Paul. - Hi, Phoebe.
你最近好吗
How are things going with you?
挺好的
Can't complain.
-我也很高兴见到你  -我很好
- Great to... - Ross, good to see you too.
你们保重
You take care.
菲比  你刚才跟钱德勒
Hey Pheebs, what was the deal with you and Chandler
为什么见到我们就跑
blowing us off before?
是啊  很怪吧
Yeah! That was so weird, huh?
菲比  为什么要这样
Phoebe, why’d you do it?
不是我  是钱德勒
l didn't do it. lt was Chandler.
他...他在生你们的气
He's mad at you.
-为什么  -拜托  你明知故问
- What? Why? - Oh, please. l think you know why.
我想不起来了
l can't think of anything.
罗斯  你是古生物学家  再往深处探究
Come on. You're a paleontologist. Just dig a little deeper.
等等  是不是因为两个星期前
Wait a minute. ls it because Joey and l
乔伊和我没找他去看尼克队的球赛
didn't invite him to that Knicks game a couple of weeks ago?
你觉得他会为这种事生气吗
ls that something he'd be mad at you for?
-应该会  -那就是啦
- l guess it could. - Well, then l think that's it.
他生气就直说嘛  干嘛隐瞒情绪
lf he's angry, he really shouldn’t just cover it up.
真希望他能直接告诉我
l wish he'd just tell me the truth.
想知道真相的话  你可以抓他去冲热水
Oh, if that's what you want, then you should run him under hot water
再抓他的头撞桌子
and bang his head against the table.
宝贝  我在"中国花园"订了位  可以吗
Honey, l made a reservation at China Garden. ls that okay?
可以啊  很棒
Yeah, that's great.
但你先跟我说说话
But first, talk to me. Talk to me.
说说你今天好不好
Tell me about your day.
蛮好的
lt was fine.
好吧
Okay.
你在想什么  你现在在想什么
Hey, what are you thinking? What are you thinking right now?
我在想你穿这件裙子很好看
I'm thinking that you are looking really fine in that dress.
太好了  保罗  但是...
Yeah, that's great, Paul. But, you know....
我想知道...哇  好结实啊
l want to know what... Wow, those are really great!
我想知道
l just want to know what,
这坚强沉默的外表下  隐藏着什么
...what is behind this strong, silent exterior?
俗语说静水深流
You know they say that still waters run deep,
我想在你的心中畅游
and l want to swim in yours.
你是想跟我做爱吗
Are you talking about having sex?
不是  保罗
No, Paul.
我一点也不了解你
l don't know anything about you.
例如  你的童年  聊聊你的童年
You know, like-like your childhood! Tell me about your childhood!
很普通
Normal.
好  那青春期呢
Okay. Then how about puberty? Come on!
青春期总是很多惨事
That's always a painful time.
朋友找你去过夜聊天
You know, your friends have a slumber party
然后趁你睡着
and stick your hand in warm water...
把你的手放进热水里  害你在睡袋里撒尿
...while you sleep, so you pee in your sleeping bag.
我没碰过那种事
No, that never happened to me.
那是你走运  没碰上贱人莎朗·麦杰斯基
You're lucky you never met that bitch, Sharon Majeski.
总之...
Anyway....
其他时期有什么悔恨吗
The rest of you life, you know?Any regrets?
没有
Nope.
保罗  我要求得不多
All right Paul, l'm not asking for a lot here. Okay?
你就讲一件事  什么事都好
Just give me something. Anything.
-好吧  -来吧
- Okay. - Okay.
六岁那年  我想要一辆大脚踏车
When l was 6 years old, l wanted a Big Wheel.
而我父母却送我一个
And instead, my parents got me this little...
小鸡造型的跳跳乐
...plastic chicken that you hop around on.
蠢毙了  小朋友都笑我
lt was embarrassing. Kids made fun of me.
那一年蛮痛苦的
That was a pretty tough year.
太好了  你看吧
That's great! See?
我觉得我比较了解你了  谢谢
l already feel like l know you a little better. Thank you.
好  现在我们可以去吃饭了  走吧
Okay, come on. Now we can go eat. Let's go!
那年真的好惨
lt was horrible.
大家都叫我鸡弟弟
They called me "chicken Boy. "
五年级我跟别人打架  其实也不算打架
ln fifth grade, l got in a fight. Well, it wasn’t really a fight.
理查·达伦咬我的鼻子  我摔倒
Richard Darinvel bit me on the nose and, and I fell down.
这里留了一个小疤  你应该看得见吧
l still have a little scar right here. You can see it.
有  我看见了
Yeah, yeah. l see the scar.
保罗  我觉得你这样很棒
Listen, Paul, I think this is really great that-that
你跟我分享你的心情
you know, you've shared your feelings.
真的...真的很好
lt's really.... lt's beautiful.
那不如我们一起去分享下食物吧
But what do you say we go share some food?
我现在吃不下
No, l couldn't eat now.
等着  你在说什么
What?! Wait! What are you talking about?
你最爱吃宫保鸡丁了
You love their Kung Pao chicken!
鸡
Chicken?
-鸡弟弟  -天啊  对不起
- Chicken Boy! -  My God, I’m sorry!
抱歉  我不是故意的  真的是无心的
I'm sorry! I didn't mean to do that! I wouldn't do that!
一无所获  我们逛了几百家戒指店
Nothing! This is the nine millionth ring store we’ve been to
还是找不到完美的戒指
and l can't find the perfect ring.
丑  丑  丑
Ugly ring, ugly ring, ugly ring....
这些戒指真美
lt's a beautiful selection.
好吧  不然你不要送戒指
OK. So maybe you don't get her a ring.
送点不一样的
Maybe you do something different.
例如订婚手镯
You know? Maybe you get her an engagement bracelet,
或是订婚皇冠
you know? Or an engagement tiara?
订婚独立战争毛瑟枪
An engagement Revolutionary War musket!
真高兴我是选了你来帮忙
You know, l'm so glad l picked you to help me with this.
你能不能想像你单膝跪下
Huh? Can you still imagine getting down on one knee
然后把这件漂亮的火器交给她
...and handing her this gorgeous piece of weaponry?
我还是送戒指好了
Yeah, I'm gonna stick with the ring.
这只好漂亮  我喜欢这只  先生
This one's nice. I like this one! Sir?
好心的先生  我想看这枚戒指
Kind sir, can l see this one?
慢着  你找我来  就是为了此刻
Wait a minute, no, this is, this is the reason you brought me. Okay?
我是讲价高手
I know how to haggle.
-所以接下来交给我处理  -有什么需要吗
- So let me handle this from here on out. - Can l help you?
有  我想看那枚戒指
Uh-uh, yes. I would like to see that ring please.
或是不看  随便
Or not. Whatever.
这是一只二零年代的戒指
This ring is from the 1920s.
1.5克拉  两侧镶有蓝宝石
it's a one and a half carat diamond with sapphires on either side.
先生  你能不能...
Sir, could l ask you...?
拿着戒指向我求婚
Could you hold out that ring and ask me to marry you?
-好吧  -来吧
- Okay. - Okay.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
天啊  就是它了  就是这个戒指
Oh, my God, that's it! That's the ring!
-多少钱  -钱德勒  让我来
- How much is it? - Chandler, I-I will handle this.
多少钱
How much is it?
8600美元
$8600.
我给你10块钱
We will give you $10.
-你到底想不想买  -想  想
- Are you interested in this ring? - Yes. Yes.
但我只能出8000块
But l can only pay $8000.
-好  8000块可以  -我们坚持10块钱
- Okay. l can let it go for 8. - We stand firm at $ 10.
-您要怎么付帐  -刷卡
- How would you like to pay? - Credit card.
不对  我的卡在乔伊那
Oh no! No-no, but I left my credit card to Joey.
我回去拿  你守住戒指
OK l'll go get it. You guard the ring.
刚才很抱歉
Listen, l'm sorry about before.
你们有10块钱的东西吗
Do you have anything here for $ 10?
有  我有两张崭新的
Uh yes, I have these two rather beautiful...
5元钞票
...five- dollar bills.
我出1块钱跟你买
l'll give you $ 1 for them.
昨天钱德勒和菲比  不是看到我们就跑吗
Remember how Chandler and Phoebe blew us off yesterday?
有吗
No.
-你当时在吃披萨  -对
- Remember, you were eating pizza? - Yeah.
记得了吧
OK.
钱德勒是在气我们两星期前
Well, apparently Chandler’s angry at us
没帮他买球票
for not getting him a ticket
一起去看尼克队的比赛
to that Knicks game a couple of weeks ago.
我们为什么要帮他买票
Oh, we’re supposed to just get him a ticket?!
那家伙老是占我们便宜
That guy's always mooching off of us.
但我还是觉得应该设法和解
Anyway, l still think we should try to patch things up, you know?
或许我们可以邀请他
Like uh, maybe we could get him tickets
送他尼克斯队其他比赛的门票
to another Knicks game and invite him.
好主意  而且他的卡还在我这里
That's a great idea. And l still have his credit card.
帐单
Here you go.
我来付吧  拿去吧
Hey, hey. l got this one. Here you go.
有时候我真搞不懂钱德勒
You know, sometimes l just don't get Chandler.
我和他做很多事都没找你
You know, me and him do stuff all the time without you,
你也不会生气
and you don't get all upset.
-很多事吗  -可多了
- All the time? - All the time.
我的天啊   我的天啊
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
-还在哭吗  -跟小女生一样
- Still crying? - Like a little girl.
我知道...都是我不好
l know, l know. This is all my fault.
是我要他敞开心胸的
l wanted him to open up.
但是我不知道我会放出一头
But l didn't know that l was gonna unleash...
哭哭啼啼又黏人的怪物
...this weepy, clingy, moist monster!
要让一个男人闭嘴只有两招
l only know of two ways to shut a man up.
其中一招是性爱
One of them is sex.
-另一个是什么  -不知道
- What's the other? - I don’t know,
我没有需要使出第二招的时候
I've never had to use the other one.
只是说做爱的时候  他就不会讲话了
I'm just saying, if we're having sex, he's not talking.
没错  每次都是你在出声
That's right. You're the talker.
总之这个主意很棒
Anyway, great idea.
我要去商店
I gotta go to the store;
我答应要去帮他买面纸
I told him that I would buy him some more tissues.
-我们这里有...  -你们没有
- We have some here. - No, you don't!
好  我还想试戴皇冠
Okay. l'd also like to try on the tiara.
太好了
Oh, yeah. Okay.
怎么样  会太过吗
What do you think? Too much?
-有一点  -好吧
- A tad. - Okay.
把头饰放回去
Then, take the tiara back
毛瑟枪再给我一次
...and let me hold the musket again.
少了点什么...
Something's missing.
把我朋友挑的戒指拿给我
Okay oh, let me see the ring my friend picked out.
那枚二零年代公主式切割的钻戒呢
Where's the 1 920s princess- cut ring?
刚刚卖给那位先生了
l just sold it to that gentleman.
完蛋了
Oh, my God!
等等  别走
Wait, no!
放我出去  快点
Let me out! Now!
瑞秋
Rachel?
不是
No.
-保罗  你好吗  -还好
- How are you, Paul? - Okay.
钱德勒
Chandler...
-你爸抱过你吗  -没有  他抱过你吗
- did your dad ever hug you? - No. Did he hug you?
不是
No! No.
只是我爸都没抱过我
lt's just that my dad never did.
我好想念我爸
l miss my dad.
你可以去赌城  看我爸亲别人的爸爸
You can see my dad in Vegas kissing other dads.
-钱德勒  -怎样
- Hey, Chandler? - Yeah?
你能不能...
Would you...?
你能不能抱我
Would you hug me?
我有点忙呢  保罗
l'm a little busy here, Paul.
跟我爸说的一模一样
That’s exactly what my dad used to say!
好啦  一下下  快点
Okay. A quick one. Come on, hug it out.
行了吧
There you go.
好了
Okay.
-再五秒钟  -够了
- Five more seconds... - Okay!
-乔伊  -怎  怎么...
- Joey! - What? Hey, what...?
保罗是吧
Hi. Paul, is it?
-我的信用卡在吗  -在  在我的...
- Do you have my credit card? - Yeah. lt's in my....
我的口袋里
ln my pocket.
-后面的口袋  后面  -幸好
- My back pocket! My back pocket! - Thank God.
我买了今天晚上尼克队的票
Oh hey listen I got us tickets to a Knicks game tonight.
我不能去
l can't go.
去啦  多好啊
Come on! lt'll be fun.
我  你  罗斯  还有保罗吧
Me, you, Ross and Paul, probably.
钱德勒  我找到最完美的戒指了
Chandler, l found the perfect ring.
那个啊  还不错
Oh, that's uh, that's pretty nice
但我还是买之前那款好了
but I’m gonna go with the one I picked first.
天啊  钱德勒  你选的那枚戒指没了  没戏了
Oh, wake up. Chandler! The one you picked is gone. lt's over!
什么
What?
被一个人买走了
Some guy bought it.
对不起  我想拦住他  却被关进监狱里
I'm sorry. I tired to stop it but they put me in jail!
-什么监狱啊  -门和门中间的小监狱
- They put you in jail? - The little jail between the doors!
菲比  我要你守着那枚戒指
Phoebe, I asked you to guard the ring!
我知道  对不起
l know. l'm sorry.
但是这枚比较好啊
But you know, this ring is better!
莫妮卡根本没看过另一枚啊
Monica never even saw the other ring.
但是他用那枚戒指向我求婚时
Yeah, but when he proposed to me with the ring,
我都起鸡皮疙瘩了
l got goosebumps.
-也许是因为那个男的  -是因为那枚戒指
- Maybe it was the guy. - lt was the ring!
给他买票他兴奋吗
Hey! So uh, was he excited about the tickets?
不  他回绝了
No! He blew us off!
-什么  -就是啊
- What? - l know.
真是太扯了
l can't believe it.
告诉你个事
Can l tell you something?
我现在有点气他
l'm a little mad at him now!
我也告诉你件事
Can l tell you something?
我也是
Me too!
他生气不告诉我们
You know what? He didn't want to talk to us about being angry,
那我们也不跟他说了
well maybe we don't talk to him at all!
-把他打入冷宫  -没错
- Freeze him out. - That's right!
-我喜欢  -给他好看
- l like it. - We'll show him.
以后就是乔伊与罗斯  最佳拍档
From now on, it's gonna be Joey and Ross, best friends.
我们将是新的乔伊与钱德勒
We'll be the new Joey and Chandler.
我回来了
Hi, l'm back.
我有好多话想对你说  我都写下来了
Hey! I have so much more to tell ya, I've written it all down!
真好
Oh, that's great.
真是太好了
No, actually, that's....
好棒  真的好棒
That's great. That's really great.
说真的  写东西
You know, l gotta tell you, writing,
写东西会燃起...
all that writing, it gets me....
我的欲火
lt gets me kind of hot.
等等  你听着
Wait, wait. Listen to this:
你知道我小时候想当什么吗
Know what l wanted to be at that age?
情圣
A lover?
-冲浪者  -是吗
- A surfer. - A surfer?
我想与海浪为伍
l wanted to be one with the waves...
等等  亲爱的  等一下
Okay, honey. Hold on real quick, hold on a second.
让我把自己...弄得舒服一点
Let me just get a little more comfortable here.
等一下
Wait a second.
-这样会不会太露了  -不会
- This isn't too revealing, is it? - No.
当年那个小家伙上哪了呢
Whatever happened to that little dude?
充满梦想...
So full of dreams.
我不在乎那个小家伙
l don't care about the little dude!
我不行了  我听不下去了
l can't! l cannot listen to any more of this!
你知道谁才会想听这些话吗  心理医师
Y’know, the only person who would want to listen to this is a mental health professional!
那还是因为他们一小时赚100块
That's only because they get $ 100 an hour!
你知道我听到现在可以赚多少吗
Do you know how much money l could have made listening to you?
2000块
$2000!
你知道我什么时候算出来的吗
Know when l figured that out?
在你说个不停的时候
While you were talking!
你居然想扼杀我的情绪  14个小时前
l can't believe you're trying to stifle me when 14 hours ago...
我们才发现  那就是我妈的目的
we figured out that's what my mother was trying to do to me!
对不起
l'm sorry.
我不是想扼杀你的情绪
l don't mean.... l didn't mean to stifle you.
我只是有点受不了
This is all just a little overwhelming.
瑞秋  对不起
Oh Rachel, l'm so sorry.
我不是故意的
l didn't mean to overwhelm you.
只不过情绪一发泄
lt's just that when those gates open...
就会...不可收拾
...it's hard to close them.
不过现在没事了  真的
But they are closed now. Believe me.
我很高兴你跟我分享你的心情
l'm so glad. l'm so glad you shared.
也很高兴你分享完了
And l'm glad that you're done.
那我们要不要...
So what do you say we....
我求之不得
l'd like that.
那真是...太棒了
That was so good!
我居然听你的话
I can't believe I let you talk me
买下这枚像是从口香糖贩卖机弄来的戒指
into buying this stupid gumball machine looking ring!
它才不像从口香糖贩卖机弄来呢
It’s not a stupid gumball machine looking ring!
它是枚很漂亮的戒指
lt's a beautiful ring!
它才不漂亮
No, it's not.
另一枚戒指
When l looked at the other ring,
我能想象到她收到时的表情
l could see Monica's face when I gave it to her, y’know?
她点头答应的模样
...and l could see her saying yes.
而这枚戒指怎么看都只是戒指
When I look at this ring, all I see is a ring!
只有我超近距离看
Unless l look at it really closely,
那才能看到我眼睛的摸样
and then l can see my own eye.
听着  这是我这辈子最重要的一件事
Look, this is the most important thing I'm gonna do in my life.
我想做到最完美
I wanna make sure it's perfect.
我们或许能把那枚戒指要回来
Maybe we could get the other ring back.
我偷听到那个人跟售货员说
'Cause I heard the guy tell the jeweler
他准备求婚的地方
where he was going to propose.
或许我们可以说服他交换什么的
So maybe we can get him to trade rings or something.
我不能这么做
l can't do that.
你总不能给莫妮卡那枚口香糖戒指吧
You certainly can't give her that stupid gumball ring.
就是他
There he is.
好  他还没求婚
Okay and he hasn’t proposed yet
因为她手指上没有戴戒指
because she has no ring on her finger.
你真行  之后我们应该去当侦探
Wow, you're good! After this, we should solve crimes.
去请他过来
Okay. Go get him.
好
Oh, okay.
抱歉先生  请您来一下
Excuse me sir? Could you come with me please?
有您的电话
You have a phone call.
-是谁  -是您公司打来的
- Who is it? - lt's your office.
-你知道是谁吗  -约翰
- Do you know who at my office? - John.
约翰啊  太好了
Oh, John! Great!
-他来了  -你好
- There he is. - Hi. Okay.
珠宝店出了点小差错
Hi. Okay, there was a slight mix-up at the jewelry store,
你拿来求婚的戒指  本来是为我保留的
the ring you're about to propose with was supposed to be held for me.
所以我得跟你要回来
So l'm gonna need to have that back.
不过作为交换  我愿意拿这枚美丽的
But, in exchange I’m willing to trade you this beautiful,
更昂贵的戒指
more expensive ring.
要是我就换
Wow, l would trade.
的确很美  但是我要用这一枚
lt is beautiful, but l'm gonna use this one.
抱歉  失陪了
Now, if you'll excuse me.
这位是我的未婚妻  她就是要这枚戒指
No-no! This is my fiancee and her heart was set on that ring.
你不会想伤她的心吧
You don't want to break her heart now do you?
对啊  你想伤一位垂死女人的心吗
Yeah. Do you want to break a dying woman's heart?
你要死了
You're dying?
她快死于...
Yeah, she's dying...
咳嗽了
...of a cough, apparently.
对  我临死前想拥有那枚戒指
Yes, it's my dying wish to have that ring.
如果我不能不能戴着它入土
See, if I'm not buried with that ring
我会变成冤鬼  永世不去投胎
then my spirit is going to wander the nether world for all eternity.
够了  亲爱的
Okay, that’s enough honey!
我不晓得
Oh, l don't know.
-再让我看一次  -当然  请看
- Let me see it. - Great. Okay, here.
-好吧  -谢谢  谢谢  谢谢
- All right, l'll do it. - Thank you. Thank you!
你即将要嫁给一个大好人
And you are about to marry a wonderful man!
拜托  我要娶一个死人呢
Hey, l'm marrying a dead woman!
兄弟们
Guys?
我有大事要宣布
l've got something important to tell you.
兄弟们
Guys?
我要跟莫妮卡求婚了
l'm gonna ask Monica to marry me.
我们应该让他从冷宫出来了吧
l think we gotta end the freeze-out.
等等  你是来真的吗
Wait. ls this for real?
对  戒指在这里
Yeah. Check out the ring.
天啊
Oh, my God!
你们俩是认真的吗
So you two are really serious?
应该吧
Yeah, pretty much.
你们要结婚了
You're gonna get married?
我们要成为连襟了  过来
We're gonna be brothers-in-law! Come here!
我们又可以当朋友了
And we're gonna be friends again.
什么
What?
-过去的事就别提了  -好吧
- Water under the bridge! Forget it! - Okay.
我本来想等搞定再说
l was gonna wait till it was official, you know.
但我还是忍不住要告诉你们
but l had to tell you guys.
因为你们是我的死党
Cause you're my best friends.
我要哭了
l think l'm gonna cry.
别再哭了  拜托
Oh! No more crying!
我刚甩掉一个爱哭宝宝  小心我也甩了你
Please, l just dumped one crybaby. l'll dump you too.
我要跟莫妮卡求婚
l'm gonna ask Monica to marry me.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
钱德勒  你们会好幸福的
Oh, Chandler! You guys are gonna be so happy!
-我知道  -面纸都死哪去了
- l know. - Where's all the tissues?!
这是戒指
Check out the ring.
很好  至少有1.5克拉
Oh, nice. One and a half carat, easy.
菲比
Hey, Pheebs.
钱德勒要跟莫妮卡求婚了
He's gonna ask Monica to marry him.
我知道  是我陪他去挑戒指的
Oh I know! And l helped pick out the ring.
你先告诉她  却没告诉我们
You told her before you told us?
我在看戒指目录时被她撞见了
She walked in while l was looking at the ring brochures.
你们能谅解的  对吧
You can understand that, right?
兄弟们
Guys?